‪PREVIOUSLY ON ‪CHOSEN HOME
Genichi Hatano, a man afraid of love
after a comment made
by a marriage agency staff
begins to change.
Love and revolution.
His love interest, Saku Sakuta,
is a middle school teacher.
Saku’s student,
Hotaru Kusunoki,
shows up carrying 30 million yen.
Party A’s mother, Tomoe Kusunoki,
is wanted for embezzlement
from her company and is on the run.
- Not wanting to see Hotaru suffer,
- Please.
Genichi decides to pose as her father.
But…
I'm Jin Ichigaya.
Your stage name is Genichi Hatano?
…to the police,
he tells a lie far too big to sustain.
- Hey.
- That lie is then
exposed instantly
when Hotaru's real dad appears.
You’ve been lying all this time?
And finally, a confession.
I like you.
Meanwhile, Hotaru’s mom
continues her runaway journey,
wandering across Japan.
I won’t be coming home for a while.
- I'll be back.
- Excuse me!
Yes?
TAMOTSU’S LITTLE GIFT SHOP
The day before yesterday,
or maybe the day before that,
I think, I sent a letter to Tokyo.
- Right.
- Has it arrived by any chance?
Did you send it out by mistake, perhaps?
Why do you ask?
You sound like you wished
it wasn't sent out.
Ah, no…
I’m not sure.
Maybe I did send it to the wrong place.
I honestly don’t know myself too.
I said…
I like you!
Huh?
Because I like you.
Saying to use a house as a "clamp"
and accompanying you to the viewing…
I did those things…
because…
I like you.
But more importantly…!
What's more important?
We’re talking about Hotaru.
If exposed, you’ll be arrested.
Right.
What if her biological dad
decides to report you?
That’d be bad.
You even lied to the police.
You told Ms. Matsu
your name was Jin Ichigaya.
That "Genichi Hatano" was a stage name
when you were aiming to be
a musician and stuff.
- That part is true.
- What?
I did aim to be a musician.
That's beside the point!
Using a fake name is the real problem, no?
Pull yourself together!
Are you still going to act as her parent?
I already signed the contract.
Come on…
What’s this? A strategy meeting?
‪-Got you!
‪-Something like that.
No, it’s not!
He's definitely gonna show up again.
- I’ll keep an eye out too.
- You're fine with this?
- Huh?
- You're his accomplice then.
You know…
That's actually kinda cool!
What? Come on!
- Okay.
- Your hand.
For Hotaru’s sake,
we’re in this together!
Y-Yeah…
You need to be more enthusiastic!
- One more time.
- Okay.
- For Hotaru’s sake,
- let's do this together!
- let's do this together.
That’s different from just now.
‪-"Let’s do this together."
‪-Again?
‪-Say, "Let’s do this together."
‪-Yes, "Let’s do this together."
TO HOTARU KUSUNOKI
Let's do this together… Got it.
Let's do this together!
- One last time. Now, hold this.
- This?
- Give it your all.
- Yes.
Let's do this together!
Wait for me!
MAY I ASK A QUESTION?
IF A COMPLETE STRANGER PRETENDS TO BE
A MINOR’S PARENT, IS THAT A CRIME?
IN SOME CASES, THIS MAY BE CONSIDERED
A CRIMINAL OFFENSE
YOU MAY BE CHARGED WITH FORGERY
VIOLATION OF THE CHILD WELFARE ACT
YOUTH PROTECTION LAWS
THE MINOR OFFENSES ACT, ETC.
POSSIBLE APPLICABLE OFFENSES ARE…
Mr. Sakuta.
One moment, please.
Yes?
What's the matter?
That man’s been loitering around,
hasn’t he?
Why are you here today?
THIS IS THE REAR GATE. PLEASE USE
MAIN ENTRANCE. NO UNAUTHORIZED VEHICLES
To see my daughter. Is there an issue?
Is this about the money?
She's definitely hiding it.
There’s no way my ex-wife
would embezzle money just for herself.
She’s too much of a coward.
If she really did it,
then it had to be for Hotaru.
So, do you know anything about it?
No.
What about that man, then?
The fool that's calling himself her dad.
I found out on that day too
that he’s not really her dad.
Could it be
you swing that way too?
That guy is gay, right?
So, I thought maybe
you're in on it with him.
Are you going to report him then?
No way.
If he gets arrested,
I have to take care of Hotaru then.
Never in hell.
So, you really…
All you really care about
is the money, huh?
What else could there be?
Then could you please stop coming here?
Oh, come on. I'm her dad.
She didn’t come to school today.
Please leave.
Thank you!
PARFAIT
- Mr. Hatano!
- Hello.
THE SETTING SUN
I love the parfaits here.
I come every now and then.
SHOPS & REST HOUSE FOOD
Me too.
It’s a treat to myself for doing well.
Um, what's that?
"Love and revolution"…
I was wondering what it meant.
The other day, I just randomly quoted
from 10 Quotes That Touch Your Heart.
It's a short video I came across,
and I just said it to you as-is.
I see now.
At work, I tend to say things
just to look cool.
Sorry about that.
Don't worry about it.
- That's why you're reading that?
- Yes.
For my own learning.
Right.
Have you not read it?
I did a long time ago.
What was it about again?
To put it simply,
it’s like fighting old morals.
I get how the characters feel,
but their actions make no sense.
The heroine's "love and revolution"
basically means
having a child with a married man
and raising it herself.
That’d make headlines these days.
Right?
But…
maybe that's just how things
are meant to be.
Everyone has their own
"love and revolution", I guess?
Really?
How’s your "love and revolution" going,
Mr. Hatano? Any progress?
- I guess so?
- What?
I confessed my love.
Really?
He doesn’t seem
all that interested, though.
Then make him interested.
How?
Convince him it’s fate.
We met at the agency,
then again at the park?
That's all fate, right?
Wait, both of us?
Something like that!
- Right.
- Yeah.
Is that also some kind of quote
or something?
Oh, no.
This is from a book called
100 Foolproof Love Techniques.
Don’t you think
the number of fences increased?
Did it?
It used to only go this far.
Now that you mention it…
What if they keep adding more,
and there's nowhere left for us to go?
Even fill the roads with fences?
Like all over the place.
What do we do if we're surrounded?
Coming.
- What's wrong?
- Just for a bit.
Could it be your dad came again?
Nope, he didn't.
Then you must be hungry.
Oh, before I forget.
Here. A spare key.
Just in case your dad shows up again.
Or, you know,
if you ever get hungry,
feel free to grab anything
from the fridge.
Then…
I’ll water the plants in return.
Thank you.
Did Mr. Sakuta agree to help too?
What?
You two talked about it yesterday, right?
I didn’t say it outright,
but I feel like Sakuta would understand.
It's easier for me
if I think positively anyway.
- Thinking positively, you say?
- Yeah.
I’m starting the laundry first,
so you'd have to wait
before dinner is ready.
Okay.
Yes?
Now? I'm doing laundry…
Sorry about this.
No, it's fine.
Did her dad come by again, by any chance?
No.
He came to the school today.
What happened then?
- I told him Hotaru was absent and he left.
- Okay.
She's his daughter, and yet that guy
really doesn’t seem to care about her.
If I were Hotaru, I’d probably
just, you know,
hate everything.
Her mom’s gone somewhere,
and her dad’s like that.
But…
when I was deceived into thinking
you were her dad…
Sorry about that.
To be frank,
I did feel you were unreliable.
Still, I was glad.
That she had a dad
who was trying his best.
I was really happy for her.
So… Well, it may be wrong.
No, it's wrong on all levels.
But for the effort she's putting in,
I'd like to respect it.
Does that mean…
I support you
in pretending to be her parent.
Are you sure that's okay?
- What?
- I mean, you're a teacher.
If this gets exposed,
wouldn't you be forced to resign?
Well…
I'm fine with that.
I don't even like school to begin with.
And yet you became a teacher?
I wanted to be a teacher
who doesn’t like school.
Wow.
It's weird, right?
No, being who you want to be
is impressive.
I hated school too.
Hold up.
- Isn’t this fate?
- Huh?
Fate.
- What is?
- Never mind.
It's nothing. Sorry.
Anyway, the next strategy meeting.
I'll be there.
Okay.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
What's wrong?
- Hey. Get in.
- What do you want?
- Don't touch me.
- Huh?
Sit tight.
Wait, what? Huh?
What in the world?!
- It's a kidnapping! Call the police!
- Kidnapping?
But it's her biological dad.
Even if we call the police…
I-Is that so?
I'm not sure.
What's that?
A letter?
- From Hotaru?
- Did she run away from home?
"To Hotaru.
Let's meet at Lakeside Café.
Make sure
to bring the money with you.
From Tomoe Kusunoki."
That's Hotaru's mom.
Is it really her, though?
Asking her to bring the money?
It could be the work of her dad.
If that's the case,
then it's unforgivable!
Hotaru thinks it's her mom, right?
But I feel like she’d be able
to see through it.
Ah, on the back.
FROM HOTARU KUSUNOKI
"So, I'll be taking the suitcase back.
From Hotaru Kusunoki."
Sorry, make way.
It's gone…
I can go on my own.
It's okay. I'll take you there.
To Lakeside Café.
How did you know about it?
I checked your mailbox.
If she were to contact anyone,
it'd be you.
I went ahead and read it.
So, you did have the money
with you all along.
MR. SAKUTA
Oh, uh…
- Sorry!
- No, I'm sorry!
I'm really sorry about this!
- Wait, I thought this place was…
- I'm sorry!
- Sorry.
- I'm really sorry!
- What's wrong?
- I'm so sorry!
If you just want the money,
why not just grab this and scram?
After I drop you off.
Do you want to see Mom?
Of course not.
Aren't you doing this for the money?
- I am.
- Then I don't get this entire situation.
They don't have a car, right?
- Who, Mom?
- No.
My current dad?
Since you probably haven’t been
out anywhere, you're happy, right?
Back when the three of us
used to go out together.
Here, both of you can share these.
Thank you!
We're not going out on a field trip.
Oh, this is nostalgic!
My parent's home always had this.
Stuff like this
might disappear eventually.
They stopped selling a lot
of these recently, right?
Enjoy it while you can.
Thank you. We'll be off now.
INOKASHIRA APARTMENTS
Have a safe trip!
These days,
there’s been a lot of talk
about vacant houses.
Our company is actually looking to expand
into that kind of business.
Um, you'll be reporting me
to the police, right?
The police?
Ah, you did trespass.
Well, yeah.
You don’t have a home?
It’s complicated.
I'm really, really in a pinch.
Please, I’m begging you…
Just don’t report me.
Oh! I’ll give you this in return.
Take whichever ones you like…
Oh, I have oranges too.
And this.
You can take them all if you want.
‪Yeah.
Are you perhaps…
a backpacker?
What?
So, you’re using this place
as a sort of lodging, huh?
- Sorry about this.
- So, how was it living here?
- What?
- Well…
I'm asking because we’re about
to put it on the market.
Is there anything you liked about it?
Hmm…
Nothing?
Well…
Oh, yes!
You haven’t noticed, right?
Sorry, what?
Never mind.
Here, take your pick.
You've been using that car ever since?
What's wrong with that?
Mom said it’s a waste,
with just the three of us.
Did she?
And then the argument started.
Do you like that car?
The old commercial they did was awesome.
The husband, wife, kids,
grandparents, even a big dog,
they all go to the beach.
Seeing the whole family goofing around,
the dad just casually
takes off his sunglasses
and goes,
"This is a man’s happiness!
A man’s car is this and whatnot."
It was a wonderful ad.
Want something to drink?
I'll have some later.
Okay.
- How about some snacks?
- I said later!
Oh, okay.
Fine, I’ll take the jelly.
Sure.
I like these too.
- Is this fate?
- Huh?
Sorry. Forget what I said.
Here you go.
Thanks.
- So, Hatano…
- Yes?
How open are you about it?
You mean, coming out?
Hotaru’s dad
confronted me and asked,
"You swing that way too?"
That’s because he saw us together.
Sorry about that.
Oh, no. I might’ve mentioned this before,
but I don’t really hide it.
I’m a bit careful at school,
since it'd be a hassle.
But I was wondering
how you handle it, Hatano.
Personally, my family back home knows,
and my best friend…
- The property agent?
- Yes.
And lastly, Hotaru.
That's about it.
Well…
If we’re talking about people
I’m close with, that is.
I only tell those I trust.
Okay.
Oh, but Yoshida too.
Along with…
Hotaru's dad. It couldn't be helped.
We’ve got time. Let's check it out.
NO PLANS FOR DISCHARGE
It says no water release today.
Why does it have to be him?
Huh?
He's gay, right?
You're one to talk.
I realized I was gay
when I touched his beard.
Really?
He was my senior from middle school.
When I looked closely,
I noticed he had hair under his chin.
It was just a few,
but it was definitely there.
When I got to touch it,
strangely, my heart raced like crazy.
That’s when I realized,
"Oh, so this is love."
But that senior said he was going
to shave it immediately.
So, before he did, I asked for a strand.
You what?
After that, I would put
that strand by my pillow
when I went to sleep.
I wrapped it in a tissue.
But they thought it was trash
and threw it away.
I was so sad.
It was proof of my first love after all.
Of course, I couldn’t confess
to him that I liked him.
For me, that tiny hair
was the only proof that I loved someone.
I cried my eyes out.
I drove every adult around me nuts.
When the strand was gone,
it felt like the part of me
that loved him disappeared too.
But if it was gone,
that also means it existed.
That strand of hair did exist.
And so did that love.
Yeah.
What about you, Hatano? Your first love.
There was this kid in middle school too
that I really liked.
I was the same as you.
Couldn’t confess, of course,
but we got close as friends.
His name is written as "carp"
and "ascend", pronounced as "Koito".
That's a cute name.
I know, right?
We were always together.
In fact, so much so,
we were teased by our classmates.
"I bet you guys are gay!"
I got scared of being found out.
I get how you feel.
So, I joined in and teased Koito about it.
That was how we ended.
Oh…
I hurt the person I loved
and ran away.
My first love and my best friend…
I lost both at once.
But the fact they’re gone
means they did exist…
At the very least,
that’s what I want to believe.
One thing I liked…
There’s a kamidana here.
I never felt lonely,
even spending a week alone
in such a big house.
I guess it’s because of this.
Well noted.
The house I used to live in had one too.
Every morning,
I’d pray with my grandmother.
But when she passed away,
the kamidana was thrown out.
That's the norm these days.
Back then,
the security and safety
people used to pray to the gods for
can now be bought with insurance.
It's becoming less common.
Kamidana, that is.
So, they’ll just keep disappearing?
Better burn it into my memory while I can.
Let’s do that.
Take this!
What do you want?
I'm so sorry!
I didn't know you’re with the police.
Good to see you’re security-conscious.
Today, you're here for?
The other day, together
with Hotaru Kusunoki and her dad,
we had a session.
Her dad?
Yes, uh… Mr. Jin Ichigaya.
His stage name is Genichi Hatano?
He said he had pursued
a career as a musician.
What is he like?
What do you mean?
He's unusual, isn't he?
Oh, no.
He really comes across as a good dad.
Is that right?
Oops.
Have you heard him sing?
Mr. Hatano’s songs.
Oh, yes.
What kind of songs does he sing?
About not having a home,
or something like that.
Does he not have a home?
Uh, well…
He does have a home.
He lives with Hotaru, after all.
Is it a dark song?
No,
it's more on the passionate side, I’d say.
- I see.
- Is there a problem?
No, I was just curious.
Okay.
That's good.
What's good?
Ah, no, it’s nothing.
Really nothing.
Welcome!
We'll have two sets of dam curry.
Okay, two sets.
- That'd be 2,000 ye--
- What about Mom's?
- What?
- Mom's portion.
Make it three sets of dam curry.
Doesn't it feel nostalgic?
The three of us went out
on drives together.
Until I got carsick, threw up,
and got yelled at.
But oh.
The dam release!
It was so impressive that you--
I was so scared, I cried.
The dam curry.
You were saying how good it was!
I got grumpy midway
and went back to the car early.
You and Mom ate the leftover curry
and got so stuffed.
Why do you only remember those parts?
What about today? Are you having fun?
Were you trying to make it fun?
I'm better, right?
I handle things like a dad better, right?
I thought you didn’t
want to take care of me.
You're right.
So, why?
I don’t get you, seriously.
But if I don’t do better than him,
I would lose, and that's just not right.
What are you competing for?
You’ve got a new family now,
so just go and be their dad.
That’s long gone.
We divorced.
I lost everything and am totally broke.
What an idiot.
You’re the idiot here!
I'm the one who wrote that letter.
Sorry for the wait!
Just hand it over!
DAM CURRY
What the hell are you doing here?
Please give that back!
It’s not yours!
It’s hers!
Even the teacher is here?
Stop giving me more work!
Let go!
Sakuta!
Please give us three sets of dam curry!
Three? Got it.
- I'm hungry!
- I know, since we walked a lot!
- I can't wait to eat!
- You're really hungry, huh?
You love curry.
Dam curry for everyone!
Where are you running to?
A slope?
Wait!
Let go of me!
Got it!
- This is my money!
- You're wrong.
It's embezzled money!
Which means it’s not yours either!
Hey, Sakuta! Saku-- Huh?
What's going on?
- Dang it!
- That letter
was written by you, wasn't it?
Such a horrible lie!
You lied too, saying the money
was not with you!
Are you really that desperate for money?
I’m going to start all over!
What?
A completely different life!
What do you mean by that?
Different means different, duh!
Huh?
Anyway, just different, you idiot!
- I don’t understand what you’re saying!
- Damn it!
What does a gay guy even know?
You can’t even have kids!
Why would Hotaru want someone like you?
Why does she want a gay guy?
Meanwhile, I'm normal.
And she's my daughter!
And yet I can’t even be a proper dad!
Why can’t I be a man?
It's always like this! Always!
- What, got a problem?
- No.
What is it?
What's your deal? Move it!
Sakuta!
Okay, nicely done.
Oh, come on!
Sakuta!
Sorry, but I'm leaving the rest to you!
W… Wait…
This can't be happening…
It's coming. Just wait.
- Here you go. Sorry for the wait!
- It's here.
This is the dam curry.
- It really does look like a dam.
- It looks yummy!
- Wow!
- Thank you.
Kusunoki…
Hotaru!
Mr. Sakuta.
- Why are you here?
- I came with your dad.
Hatano, I meant.
Uh-huh.
Um…
- Your mom…
- She won't be coming, right?
I know.
You may eat it.
- Are you sure?
- Yes.
Here.
- I'm digging in.
- Likewise.
Let's dig in!
Oh, it's so cool!
- It really is!
- Wow.
Amazing!
- That's a big piece.
- Can you eat it?
Am I… eating this the right way?
He’s a terrible dad.
There are so many bad memories.
But there were also memorable ones.
They’re all gone now.
I can't even get to see Mom.
Everything’s gone.
If it’s gone…
that means it once existed.
Well…
That's what Hatano said.
Right.
Thank you for today.
Don't worry about it.
I got this in return, so…
You’re really kind.
You're giving me too much credit.
Thank you.
Honestly, it’s just that reporting you
to the police would be a huge hassle.
Besides, I find backpackers
kinda interesting.
For a long time,
I couldn’t really go anywhere.
I was living in Tokyo,
and I'd just go see the nearby dam.
I've been living that kind of life.
And, well, it was fine, but…
Never mind. Forget what I said.
Enjoy yourself.
And good luck finding a place to stay!
- Thank you.
- Well then.
Thank you for having me.
No, not at all.
- I’ll come again.
- To listen to his songs?
Yes.
No, to check on things.
See you.
I'll take my leave.
Are you sure I can
have them all to myself?
Yeah, no need to hesitate.
Where's my dad?
Which one?
Both.
I spilled a bit.
It's fine.
Sorry.
You good for the restroom?
Need me to stop at a roadside station?
I'm good.
You can't do this. I said no.
Ouch! You're hurting me!
What are you doing?
Damn it!
‪INOKASHIRA APARTMENTS
Were you okay?
Where's Hatano?
He went to retrieve the suitcase.
He left the rest to me, he said.
What? Will he be okay?
He really didn't have to go
that far for just a suitcase.
Wait, what did you just say?
Huh?
Hey!
- Hey, um…
- Sorry.
What… Come on!
I'm really sorry, but…
- Will you get off?
- No, sorry.
Hey!
- Get off--
- No.
The money…
What are you going to do with it?
What?
What do you want?
A house, maybe?
Why a house?
Buying a house
and using it as a "clamp"
is my personal goal.
A "clamp"?
That's "love and revolution".
You're creeping me out.
Huh?
Are you sure we can just enter?
Yeah.
It should be fine.
Please excuse me.
We're already in Tokyo!
Just get off already!
Never!
Not until I bring this back with me.
This is something precious to her!
What?
Huh?
So, you knew?
The letter wasn’t from your mom.
It doesn’t even look like her handwriting.
I wonder who’s really the idiot here.
But you went anyway.
I just thought about thinking positively.
Thinking positively?
Maybe,
just maybe,
Mom will come.
Maybe I’ll get to see her.
So, that's how it is.
Yeah.
Do you wanna go for a walk?
Did it not get to go out for a walk?
Probably…
You did it because you were asked to?
Yes.
To act as her parent?
You must have a screw loose.
I just want to do what I can right now.
Huh?
You said
you can't be a proper dad.
Well, I’ve got a lot I can’t do too.
To begin with, I’ve failed at more things
than most people. That's what I feel.
So, all I can do is what I'm able
to do every day.
And what do you know?
Things somehow turn out alright.
How so?
How should I put it?
It's like being alive…
feels good.
What are the things
you're able to do?
Like walking the dog every day.
Do they perhaps remember the route?
- Hello!
Smiling and greeting.
Hello.
- The dogs are so cute!
- Go ahead.
Giving way to others.
A grasshopper.
Releasing a bug back into the wild.
Huh? A bug?
It doesn’t have to be anything big.
Just stick to what you can handle.
I recommend it. Little by little,
that’s how you do it.
What?
Everyone has their own
"love and revolution", I guess.
What does that even mean?
Even for a person like me,
is there anything I can do?
Of course!
Will being alive
feel good?
Yeah, totally!
Don’t make it sound so easy!
Ah, wait… Hey!
Hello!
Okay, here.
Here you go.
- This is a souvenir from my business trip.
- Thank you.
I got this as a gift,
but share it with Genichi.
- Thank you.
Welcome back!
- Welcome back!
- I'm back.
INOKASHIRA APARTMENTS
You walked the dogs?
They asked us to.
Thanks.
He returned the suitcase?
Look,
could you please let me know
what's inside beforehand?
It was exhausting.
That's why I said I'm taking the suitcase.
Didn't I?
Is that what you meant?
How'd you expect me to get it?
Sorry you had to take them out.
Oh, it's okay.
There's a grasshopper on your foot.
It must've followed me from earlier.
What?
It was about to get stepped on,
so I let it back into the grass.
You have a grasshopper on you too.
Isn't this fate?
Yeah, it's fate.
Huh?
What did you just say?
DRIED SALMON
Okay, over here.
Please write your name.
- Do I have to?
- Yes.
Okay.
SAKU SAKUTA
Oh, by the way, I asked the landlord,
and I borrowed an empty unit.
- What?
- Really?
Until I find a new place to move.
Please treat me well.
Okay!
PARTY C - SAKU SAKUTA
The garden shovel
Was wet all day
Then the rain stopped
And I sneezed
After the beep tone,
please leave your name and message.
Hello, Mom?
Hey, Mom.
Remember that time the three of us
went to the dam?
NO PLANS FOR DISCHARGE
On the way back, in the car,
we all sang at the top of our lungs.
I can’t remember what song it was,
but I had so much fun.
We’ll probably never
go out together like that…
DAM CURRY
…never eat curry together,
or sing like that ever again.
But that timeline… It really existed.
Someday, tell me more
about your memories, Mom.
Talk to you soon.
The fresh laundry…
Thank you.
If you came all this way,
you must've not found a house yet.
I think it'll be soon.
Oh yeah?
I thought maybe
you had lingering feelings.
- No, not at all.
- Really?
- Yeah, nope.
- A bit cold, huh?
La la la
A rainbow, a rainbow
Stretched across the sky
And your, your
Mood cleared up too
Surely tomorrow
Will be a clear sky
Nacchi!
Hey, what's up?
Hey, Nacchi.
- What are you doing?
- She's crazy.
I'm studying.
What?
Koinobori!
- One plus one?
- How do I solve this?
- Which one?
- What's two plus…
- This.
- Make yourself at home.
- Okay.
- You can sit wherever.
- Got it.
- Thanks.
INOKASHIRA
TO KYOKO INOKASHIRA
FROM TOMOE KUSUNOKI
Subtitle translation by: Jeffery